

CANDIDATE RESUME

Masibulele Romeo Ngondo

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 25 August 1995

Residential Area: 19 Bhayi Avenue, Joe Slovo

Park, Milnerton, Cape Town, 7441

Marital Status: Single Gender: Male Race: Black African

Languages: IsiXhosa, Afrikaans, English

Criminal Record: None

Education

• 2021 – 2023: Systems Development, Cape Innovation & Technology Initiative

• 2020: Explore Data Science Academy

• 2019: Agile Web Development, Codex

• 2009 – 2013: National Senior Certificate (Matric), Murraysburg High School

Contact Details

Phone Number: 062 010 6909 / 081 456 5855 Alt. Numbers: 084 694 4267 / 078 076 5106 Email: sticky.ngondo@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/Masibulele22 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/masibulele-romeo-ngondo-7a1a05124/

Key Skills

- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, AWS, Azure, React
- Python, Pandas, NLTK, NLP, Matplotlib, SQL
- Web Development, Data Science & Analysis
- Microsoft PowerBI, Office 360, MS SSMS
- Machine Learning, Machine Vision
- Node.Js, Git & GitHub

Interests & Hobbies

Poetry, rugby, drawing, art, music, soccer, basketball, camping, hiking, rock climbing, photography, meditation and reading

About me

I am a countryboy from the Karoo who is passionate about people, problem-solving and bringing ideas to life through my creative and pragmatic abilities that contribute to good team projects. I also love researching and learning about science and technologies like software development, testing, data science, internet of things and various other emerging 4th Industrial Revolution technologies.

Achievements & Key Projects

- 21 JANUARY 30 NOVEMBER 2020 Explore Data Science Academy, Salt River: Data Science Student
- 1 APRIL 30 NOVEMBER 2019 CodeX, Cape Town: Full Stack Agile Developer Student
- 2013, Murraysburg High School Headboy & MHS SGB member
- 2013, ICDL (International Computer Driving License)
- 2012 2013, Murraysburg Child Committee Vice-Chairperson
- 2009 2013, ANEX Freelance Poetry Author & Events Speaker

Work Experience

Amazon Cape Town — Data Administrator

11 MARCH 2024 - 28 JUNE 2024: Responsible for ensuring the quality, security, and integrity of data across various platforms and applications. Using MS Excel to list and fill in missing catalog data of Amazon selling partners and ensuring online Amazon SA store catalog data is accurate.

Cape Innovation & Technology Initiative — Systems Development Technical Trainee 1 SEPTEMBER 2021 - 31 JANUARY 2023: Developing applications and websites using HTML, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL, Python, Node.Js, React in teams using SCRUM & Agile methodologies and doing presentations of products to judges and teams.

BCX Exa, Telkom SA Ltd, (Remote) — Data Integration Engineer Intern 26 AUGUST 2020 - 30 NOVEMBER 2020: Working in a team to develop a data integration pipeline for a Social Media Sentiment Analyzing application. Using cloud computing services like Amazon Web Services & Microsoft Azure.

The Foschini Retail Group, Parow — Telemarketing Agent 6 SEPTEMBER 2016 - 6 MARCH 2018: Sell, survey and market TFG consumer financial products and services e.g., health, funeral, accident, disability, and dread disease covers for TFG customers account holders.

References

- Belinda Francis, Managing Director, Tych Business Solutions (Agent to Amazon) 084 658 9000
- Eudene Goliath, Bradley Willemse, Lamla Mtyoki; IT Department: Cape Innovation & Technology Initiative, Capaciti 074 660 8888, 081 437 0476, 066 209 2430 / 021 003 7579
- Zukie Kepe, BCX Exa, Telkom SA Ltd 082 293 3904 / 011 266 5062
- Makhosandile Zukelwa, Tech Mentor: CodeX 067 156 8798
- Aqueelah Abrahams, Team Leader: TFG (Foschini) 071 442 8067 / 021 551 5961



Development Projects

South Africa

Link: https://masibulele22.github.io/south_africa/index.html

Link: https://delightful-conkies-c05d8f.netlify.app/

South Africa is a tour guide webpage that created using HTML and CSS to give tourist a quick taste of the current zeitgeist, history, places and faces of modern South Africa.

Uvelaphi

Link: https://uvelaphi.co.za/

Uvelaphi is a web and mobile platform that seeks to connect African people with their roots by increasing knowledge about African clan names. It also seeks to create an intergenerational reservoir of history for African people. I developed it using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Philisa

Link: https://jade-gelato-059094.netlify.app/

A website created to help families connect people who struggle with drug abuse to the nearest rehabilitation centers in and around Cape Town. All thanks to the collaborative effort of Amanda Fono, Asanda Mnotoza, Emihle Ntinzi, Nathan Everts & Romeo Ngondo, together better known as "The Code Millennials".

Banking Application

Link: https://github.com/Masibulele22/banking application

A simple python coded banking program I created using Jupyter Notebooks.

Liso

Link: https://github.com/Masibulele22/Liso

Liso is a facial recognition application created to help tackle crime in finding and IDing missing children or wanted suspects by police or government authorities or ordinary civilians. I created it using Python, NumPy and the OpenCV library. It is not hosted yet.

Stock Prices

Link: https://github.com/Masibulele22/simple stock prices

A simple stock price webapp that is data driven. I created it using the web application framework Streamlit and Python.

Bioinformatics DNA Count

Link: https://github.com/Masibulele22/bioinformatics dna count This program counts the nucleotide composition of query DNA.

Contact Glass Form

Link: https://stellular-sawine-dcb0cc.netlify.app/

A glass contact form made with HTML, CSS and glassmorphism design.